Guide to the John Farquhar Fulton Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Personal and Family Papers, 1884-1988; Series IV
  John F. Fulton's files include clippings and financial records, such as check counterfoils and estate papers. There are also a few drafts for Fulton's diary, including some that are handwritten. These files also contain memorabilia from milestone events and from Fulton's travels. Other files concern funeral arrangements, obituaries, and memorials.
  For John F. Fulton, Sr., there are case histories from his ophthalmological practice in nineteenth century St. Paul, Minnesota. These histories, in three bound volumes, include correspondence with patients and records of diagnoses and prescriptions.
  There is a large quantity of Lucia Pickering Fulton's correspondence in the series. Long term correspondence with several family members and a few friends is arranged under the heading "Correspondence, alphabetical." Other correspondence is arranged in chronological order. This includes correspondence concerning John Fulton's publications and posthumous business affairs. Under the heading "Letters of condolence," there are expressions of sympathy and reminiscences about and tributes to John Fulton.
  - Fulton, Edith, 1921-1932, 1946 (Box 294, Folder 1)
  - Fulton, John F.
    - Address books, Circa 1920-1955 (Box 294, Folder 2)
    - Awards, certificates, citations, 1923-1960, undated (Box 294, Folder 3)
      See also: Series VI, box 319, folder 5
    - Biographical data
      - General, 1918-1960 (Box 294, Folder 4)
      - Medical, 1937-1959 (Box 294, Folder 5)
    - Christmas gift lists, 1932-1959 (Box 294, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, 1924-1975 (Box 294, Folder 7)
    - Date books, 1904-1907, 1952-1959 (Box 295, Folder 8)
    - Death certificate, 1960 (Box 295, Folder 9)
    - Diary
    - Diary drafts
      See also: Series VI, box 319, folder 6
      - 1916, 1921-1932 (Box 295, Folder 10-13)
      - 1938-1941 (Box 295, Folder 14-15)
    - Estate, 1960-1968 (Box 295, Folder 16-19)
    - Financial
      - General, 1930-1955 (Box 296, Folder 20-21)
      - Check counterfoils
        - 1928-1933 June (Box 296, Folder 22-25)
        - 1933 July-1939 June (Box 297, Folder 26-29)
        - 1939 June-1945 February (Box 298, Folder 30-33)
        - 1945 February-1953 April (Box 299, Folder 34-37)
        - 1953 April-1960 May (Box 300, Folder 38-41)
      - Contributions
        - 1931-1941 (Box 301, Folder 42)
        - 1950-1959 (Box 301, Folder 43)
    - Funeral arrangements, 1960 (Box 301, Folder 44)
    - Itineraries, 1940-1957, undated (Box 301, Folder 45)
    - Memorabilia
      See also: Series VI, box 319, folders 7-11
      - 1918-1923 (Box 301, Folder 46)
      - 1923 [wedding] (Box 301, Folder 47)
      - 1924-1928 (Box 301, Folder 48)
      - 1926-1956 [physiological congresses]
      - 1929 (Box 301, Folder 49)
      - 1930s (Box 301, Folder 50)
      - 1931-1935, 1953 [international neurological congresses]
      - 1940s (Box 301, Folder 51)
      - 1946 [Harvard reunion] (Box 302, Folder 52)
      - 1950s
        - General (Box 302, Folder 53)
        - Lecture posters, 1951-1953
          See: Series VI, box 319, folder 12
        - Sterling chair of the history of medicine, 1951
        - First International Congress on Medical Librarianship, 1953
        - First World Conference on Medical Education, 1953
        - Rhodes Centennial, 1953
        - Rome congresses, 1954
        - 25th anniversary at Yale, 1955
        - Fifteenth International Congress of the History of Medicine, 1956
        - Eighth International Congress of the History of Science, 1956
        - 60th birthday party, 1959 (Box 302, Folder 53)
      - undated (Box 302, Folder 54)
    - Memorials
      - Contributions to Cushing Book Fund, 1960 (Box 302, Folder 55)
      - Fulton Society, 1960-1982, 1985 (Box 302, Folder 56-58)
      - Gifts, 1960-1971 (Box 302, Folder 59)
      - John F. Fulton Book Fund, 1960-1968 (Box 302, Folder 60)
        See also: Series VI, box 319, folder 13
      - John F. Fulton Memorial Fund, 1960-1973 (Box 302, Folder 61)
      - John F. Fulton Seminar Room, 1966-1967 (Box 302, Folder 62)
      - Journal of the History of Medicine, 1962 February-August (Box 303, Folder 63)
      - Laboratorio de Neurofisiologia y electroencephalographia, 1953
        See: Series V, box 317, folders 45-46
      - Memorial service volume correspondence, 1960 (Box 303, Folder 64-66)
    - Notebooks
      - 1926, undated (Box 303, Folder 67)
      - Harvard
      - Oxford
    - Obituaries, 1960-1961 (Box 303, Folder 68-69)
    - Passports, 1928-1959 (Box 303, Folder 70)
    - Will, 1936-1956 (Box 303, Folder 71)
      See also: Series VI, box 319, folder 14
  - Fulton, John F., Sr.
    - Case histories, 1891-1895 (Box 304, Folder 72-73)
    - Case histories, 1895-1898 (Box 305, Folder 74)
    - Clippings, 1929-1932 (Box 306, Folder 75)
    - Correspondence, 1924-1932 (Box 306, Folder 76)
    - Diplomas and certificates, 1880, 1932
      See: Manuscripts common folio
      See: Series I, box 4, folder 48 See: Series I, box 6, folder 76
    - Memorabilia, 1908-1932 (Box 306, Folder 77)
    - Notebook, n.d. (Box 306, Folder 78)
    - Papers read at meetings, n.d. (Box 306, Folder 79)
    - Published papers, 1924-1932 (Box 306, Folder 80)
  - Fulton, Lucia Pickering
    - Correspondence
      - Alphabetical
        - Francis, William W., 1930-1959 (Box 306, Folder 81)
        - Fulton family, 1921-1923 (Box 306, Folder 82)
        - Muirhead, Arnold, 1926-1977 (Box 306, Folder 83)
        - Wheatland, Martha [sister], 1929-1930 (Box 306, Folder 84)
        - Wheatland, Mary and Richard [parents]
          - 1922-1930 June (Box 307, Folder 85-91)
          - 1930 July-1959, undated (Box 308, Folder 92-100)
      - Chronological
        - 1919-1924 (Box 309, Folder 101-106)
        - 1925-1929 (Box 310, Folder 107-108)
        - 1930s (Box 310, Folder 109)
        - 1940s (Box 310, Folder 110)
        - 1946 [letters of condolence for father's death] (Box 310, Folder 111)
        - 1950s (Box 310, Folder 112)
        - 1959-1963, 1969, The Making of a Library (Box 310, Folder 113)
        - 1960s
          - General (Box 310, Folder 114)
          - Boyle biography, 1960-1965 (Box 310, Folder 115)
          - Journal of Neurophysiology, 1960-1962 (Box 310, Folder 116)
          - Medical Physiology and Biophysics, 1960-1962 (Box 310, Folder 117)
          - Physiology of the Nervous System, 1960-1965 (Box 311, Folder 118)
          - Selected Readings in Physiology, 1966 (Box 311, Folder 119)
        - 1970s (Box 311, Folder 120)
        - 1980s (Box 311, Folder 121)
        - n.d. (Box 311, Folder 122)
    - Letters of condolence
      - A-G, 1960-1961 (Box 311, Folder 123-126)
      - H-Z, 1960-1961 (Box 312, Folder 127-133)
      - Societies, 1960 (Box 312, Folder 134)
    - Memorabilia
      - General, 1920-1965 (Box 313, Folder 135)
      - Diary, 1922-1925 (Box 313, Folder 136)
      - Guest book, 1947-1988 (Box 313, Folder 137)
      - Party register, 1956-1965 (Box 313, Folder 138)
      - "Some Idle Reminiscences of England," 1931 (Box 313, Folder 139)
  - Fulton family [genealogical materials]
    - Correspondence with Burke's Landed Gentry, 1938-1939 (Box 314, Folder 140)
    - Drafts of genealogy, Circa 1920s-1930s, 1957-1959 (Box 314, Folder 141-142)
    - Family trees, Circa 1920s-1950s (Box 314, Folder 143)
    - Notes, Circa 1920s-1950s (Box 314, Folder 144-145)
    - Notes on John F. Fulton, Sr., 1929-1932 (Box 314, Folder 146)
    - Typescript, 1929 (Box 314, Folder 147)
  - Langford, Nathaniel P., 1884, 1911, 1939 (Box 314, Folder 148)
  - Langford family [genealogical materials], Circa 1920s-1930s (Box 314, Folder 149-150)
  - Wheatland, Mary [mother of Lucia P. Fulton]
    - Correspondence, 1923-1956 (Box 314, Folder 151)
    - "News sheets" from Dorothy, 1947 (Box 314, Folder 152)
  - Wheatland, Mary [daughter of Stephen Wheatland][diary], 1947 (Box 314, Folder 153)
  - Wheatland family [genealogical materials], Circa 1923 (Box 314, Folder 154)
  - Wheaton family [genealogical materials], ca., 1920s-1930s (Box 314, Folder 155)
- Visual Images, 1899-1965; Series V
  This series includes photo prints, negatives, sketches, and 16 mm motion picture film. These materials are arranged under four headings: "Chronological"; "Individuals"; "Buildings"; and "Film." Photographs from professional meetings and travel are filed under the heading "Chronological." Under "Individuals" there are portraits of Fulton, photographs of colleagues, friends and family, and research subjects. Photographs of Fulton's residences and offices are filed under "Buildings." Several undated reels of 16 mm. home movie film, probably made in England, perhaps in the 1920s, show social events. Additional reels include footage of experiments on research animals with impaired mobility.
  - Chronological
    - 1922 [Egypt] (Box 315, Folder 1)
    - 1923 (Box 315, Folder 2)
      See also: Series VI, box 319, folder 15
    - 1931-1932
      - General (Box 315, Folder 3)
        See also: Series I, box 4, folder 48 See also: Series I, box 6, folder 76
      - 9th International Congress of the History of Medicine, Bucharest (Box 315, Folder 4)
        See also: Series VI, box 319, folder 16
    - 1935-1938
      - General (Box 315, Folder 5)
      - 11th International Congress of the History of Science, Zagreb (Box 315, Folder 6)
      - South Pacific (Box 315, Folder 7)
    - 1939
      - General (Box 315, Folder 8)
      - 3rd International Neurological Congress, Copenhagen (Box 315, Folder 9)
      - Royal Swedish Academy of Science (Box 315, Folder 10)
    - 1940-1944 (Box 315, Folder 11)
      See also: Series VI, box 319, folder 17
    - 1945-1946 (Box 315, Folder 12)
    - 1947 (Box 315, Folder 13)
    - 1948-1949
      - General (Box 315, Folder 14)
      - 4th International Neurological Congress, Paris (Box 315, Folder 15)
    - 1951
      - General (Box 315, Folder 16)
      - University of Louvain (Box 315, Folder 17)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 315, Folder 18)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 315, Folder 19)
    - 1956 (Box 316, Folder 20)
    - 1957-1959 (Box 316, Folder 21)
    - undated (Box 316, Folder 22)
  - Individuals
    - A-C, 1920s-1950s (Box 316, Folder 23)
    - Chimpanzees and gorillas, 1931-1948 (Box 316, Folder 24)
    - D-F, 1930s-1950s (Box 316, Folder 25)
    - Dodge, Israel and Lucia [Lucia Fulton's grandparents], undated (Box 316, Folder 26)
    - Fulton, Edith and daughters, 1899 (Box 316, Folder 27)
    - Fulton, James Sample, undated (Box 316, Folder 28)
    - Fulton, John F.
      - 1906-1948 (Box 316, Folder 29-33)
        See also: Series VI, box 319, folders 18-19
      - 1949-1959 (Box 317, Folder 34-35)
        See also: Series VI, box 319, folders 20-21
      - 1956, 1965 [G. Kelly portrait] (Box 317, Folder 36)
      - undated (Box 317, Folder 37)
    - Fulton, John F. and Lucia P., 1920s-1959 (Box 317, Folder 38)
    - Fulton, John F., Sr., undated (Box 317, Folder 39)
    - Fulton, Lucia P., 1929-1958 (Box 317, Folder 40)
    - Fulton family, 1919-1959 (Box 317, Folder 41)
    - G-L, 1934-1959 (Box 317, Folder 42)
    - M-Z, 1917-1964 (Box 317, Folder 43)
  - Buildings
    - Charlesbury Road house, Oxford, 1928-1929 (Box 317, Folder 44)
    - Laboratorio de Neurofisiologia y Electroencefalografia, Uruguay, Circa 1953 (Box 317, Folder 45-46)
    - Magdalen College [Fulton's room], Oxford, 1922 (Box 317, Folder 47)
    - Mill Rock, undated (Box 317, Folder 48)
    - Physiology Library, Circa 1933 (Box 317, Folder 49)
    - Yale Historical Library [Fulton's office], 1956 (Box 317, Folder 50)
  - Film [16mm]
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - [tennis, boat races, punting in England], late, 1920s (Reel 318, Reel 1)
    - [Fulton demonstrating the impaired mobility of an experimental dog; tea party with Lucia Fulton], 1920s or 1930s (Reel 318, Reel 2)
    - [baboon walking on leash; experimental primate with impaired mobility], 1936 (Reel 318, Reel 3)
    - [dog, cats, mobility demonstration], undated (Reel 318, Reel 4)
    - [young primate], undated (Reel 318, Reel 5)
    - [cat with impaired mobility, timer and chart for distance; one trial is in slow motion], undated (Reel 318, Reel 6)
    - [primate hand and arm, experimental trials], undated (Reel 318, Reel 7)
    - [ L.P.F. and J.F.F. playing tennis; experimental dog with impaired mobility], undated (Reel 318, Reel 8)
- Oversize, Series VI
  - General Files
    - Rhodes Scholarship Trust, 1923-1929 (Box 319, Folder 1)
    - Diploma (Folder 320)
  - Special Subjects
    - Army Medical Library: Association of Honorary Consultants, Fourth Annual Meeting, 1947 (Box 319, Folder 2)
    - Harvey Cushing: A Biography [design; promotion; reviews], 1946 (Box 319, Folder 3)
  - Writings
    - Bib. 411. Frontal Lobotomy and Affective Behavior (1951) [illustration], Circa 1951 (Box 319, Folder 4)
  - Personal and Family Papers
    - Fulton, John F.
      - Awards, certificates, citations, 1948, 1951, 1957 (Box 319, Folder 5)
      - Diary drafts, 1928-1929, 1931 (Box 319, Folder 6)
      - Memorabilia
        - 1922-1923
          - General (Box 319, Folder 7)
          - Wedding (Box 319, Folder 8)
        - 1925-1929 (Box 319, Folder 9)
        - 1930s (Box 319, Folder 10)
        - 1940s (Box 319, Folder 11)
        - 1951-1953, [lecture posters] (Box 319, Folder 12)
      - Memorials: John F. Fulton Book Fund, 1964 (Box 319, Folder 13)
      - Wills, 1936-1956 (Box 319, Folder 14)
  - Visual Images
    - Chronological
      - 1923 (Box 319, Folder 15)
      - 1932 Sep [9th International Congress of the History of Medicine, Bucharest] (Box 319, Folder 16)
      - 1940-1944 (Box 319, Folder 17)
    - Individuals: Fulton, John F., 1934-1959 (Box 319, Folder 18-21)